Here we in the lesson map, just as a reminder.
これはレッスンマップです 確認のためにすぎませんが
We need the process covariance matrix to model the stochastic
プロセス共分散 行列によって遷移関数の
part of the state transition function.
確率的部分をモデル化する必要があります
First I'm going to show you how the acceleration is expressed by
まず 加速度を
the kinematic equations.
運動方程式で表す方法を示します
And then I'm going to use that information to derive the process
その次にその 情報を使用して
covariance matrix Q.
プロセス共分散行列Qを導き出します
Say we have two consecutive observations of the same pedestrian with initial and
同じ歩行者の2つの連続した観測があり 初期速度と
final velocities.
最終速度があるとします
&gt;From the kinematic formulas we can derive the current position and
&gt;運動方程式から 現在位置と
speed as a function of previous state variables, including
速度を前の 状態変数の関数として導き出すことができ これには
the change in the velocity or in other words, including the acceleration.
速度の変化 言い換えると 加速度が含まれます
You can see how this is derived below.
これは次のように導き出されることがわかります
Looking at the deterministic part of our motion model,
モーションモデルの決定論的 部分を見て
we assume the velocity is constant.
速度が一定であると仮定します
However, in reality the pedestrian speed might change.
しかし 現実には 歩行者の速度は変化することがあります
Since the acceleration is unknown, we can add it to the noise component.
加速度は不明なので ノイズ成分に追加できます
And this random noise would be expressed analytically as in the last terms in
そして このランダムノイズは 分析的に方程式の最後の項として
the equation.
表されます
So, we have a random acceleration vector in this form,
ランダム加速度 ベクターはこの形式になり
which is described by a 0 mean and the covariance matrix, Q.
これは0平均と 共分散行列Qによって記述されます
Delta t is computed at each Kalman filter step, and
デルタtが各 カルマンフィルターステップで計算され
the acceleration is a random vector with 0 mean and
加速度はランダム ベクターであり 平均0と
standard deviations sigma ax and sigma ay.
標準偏差シグマaxおよび シグマayです
This vector can be decomposed into two components.
このベクターは2つの成分に分解 できます
A four by two matrix G which does not contain random variables.
4かける2の行列Gはランダム変数を含みません
And a two by one matrix,
そして2かける1の行列Aは
A, which contains the random acceleration components.
ランダム 加速度成分を含みます
Based on our noise vector, we can define now the new covariance matrix Q.
ノイズベクターに基づいて 新しい共分散行列Qを 定義できます
The covariance matrix is defined as the expectation value of the noise vector
共分散行列はノイズベクターの 期待値
mu times the noise vector mu transpose.
ミューかけるノイズベクター ミュー転置として定義されます
So, let's write this down.
ではこれを書き留めておきましょう
As matrix G does not contain random variables,
行列Gは ランダム変数を含まないため
we can put it outside expectation calculation.
期待値の計算外に 置くことができます
This leaves us with three statistical moments.
これによって3つの 統計学的モーメントが残ります
The expectation of ax times ax, which is the variance of ax, sigma ax squared.
axかけるaxの期待値 つまりシグマaxの二乗の分散です
The expectation of ay times ay which is the variance of ay, sigma ay squared,
ayかけるayの期待値 つまりayシグマay二乗の分散と
and the expectation of ax times ay, which is the covariance of ax and ay.
axかけるayの期待値 つまりaxとayの共分散です
Ax and ay are assumed uncorrelated noise processes.
axとayは 相関関係のない ノイズプロセスとみなされます
This means that the covariance sigma ax, ay in Q nu is 0.
つまり Qニュー内の共分散シグマ ax ayは0です
So after combining everything in one matrix,
よって すべてを1つの行列に 組み合わせた後
we obtain our four by four Q matrix.
4かける4のQ行列が得られます
I also want you to be aware that sometimes in the literature,
もう一つ注意してもらいたいのは 文献では時々
Q nu might be noted as Q.
QニューがQと表記されることです
So sometimes there might be a confusion between two matrices.
したがって ときには 2つの行列が混同されることがあります
See below for more information.
詳しくは以下を参照してください